

☐ (+1) 814-777-7019 | **I**f3ixiao@gmail.com | **f**fxiao.me | **D**xiaofen9 | **D**f-xiao

Summary_

I am a software engineer at Google. I earned CS Ph.D. from Georgia Tech, where I designed adversarial approaches to improve the privacy and security of machine learning/software systems.

Published 5+ first-author research works at top-tier conferences including IEEE S&P, USENIX SEC, BlackHat USA, etc. Member of Program Committees at premium AI conferences including NeurIPS and ACM WWW.

Work Experience _____

Google CA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2023 - now

Palo Alto Networks CA, USA

SENIOR STAFF RESEARCHER Dec. 2023 - Aug, 2024

- Led the research and development of company's first adversarial GenAl product, resulting in 2 approved US patent filings and 1 top-tier academic publication.
- Design the first transformer-based Script Malware deteciton, contributing 10% detection improvement for previous false negatives.
- · Developed and optimized a machine learning feature management infrastructure, reducing data processing overhead from hours to minutes.
- · Techniques: LLM safety, Online learning, Model post-training

Google WA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN May. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Designed and implemented the Tsunami Callback Service, which enables Google Cloud Vulnerability Scanner to detect log4j-like vulnerabilities.
 My work is now open-sourced and actively maintained by Google https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner-callback-server
- Leveraged CI/CD techniques in Google to launch my project in production environments (early launch, exceeding expectation).
- · Gave two tech talks at Google. I shared my previous research works on web vulnerability analysis.
- Techniques: Java, Distributed Systems, Low-latency System Design, OWASP Vulnerability Assessment, Kubernetes.

Google WA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Made fundamental changes to the Linux virtual memory management system to enable fast I/O for Confidential VMs at Google Cloud.
- Improved Confidential VM network throughput by 20%.
- Identified a potentially serious bug in our product and received a Google Peer Bonus Award.
- Techniques: C&C++, Linux Memory Management, Linux I/O Internals, Cloud Virtualization, AMD SEV, Confidential Computing.

Education_

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jul. 2019 - Dec. 2023

• GPA: 3.9/4

Wuhan UniversityB.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Wuhan, China

Sept. 2014 - Jun. 2018

• GPA: 3.87/4

Publication

5 FIRST-AUTHOR WORKS IN TOP-TIER CONFERENCES

FaceObfuscator: Defending Deep Learning-based Privacy Attacks with Gradient Descent-Resistant Features in Face Recognition.

USENIX SEC'24

Shuaifan Jin, He Wang, Zhibo Wang, **Feng Xiao**, Jiahui Hu, Yuan He, Wenwen Zhang, Zhongjie Ba, Weijie Fang, Shuhong Yuan, Kui Ren

November 9, 2024 Feng Xiao · Résumé 1

JASMINE: Scale up JavaScript Static Security Analysis with Computation-based Semantic Explanation.

IEEE S&P'24

FENG XIAO, ZHONGFU SU GUANGLIANG YANG, AND WENKE LEE

WEBRR: A Forensic System for Replaying and Investigating Web-Based Attacks in The Modern Web.

USENIX SEC'24

JOEY ALLEN, ZHENG YANG, FENG XIAO, MATTHEW LANDEN, ROBERTO PERDISCI, WENKE LEE

Understanding and Mitigating Remote Code Execution Vulnerabilities in Cross-Platform Ecosystem.

ACM CCS'22

FENG XIAO, IAN ZHENG, JOEY ALLEN, GUANGLIANG YANG, AND WENKE LEE

Abusing Hidden Properties to Attack Node.js Ecosystem.

USENIX Security'21

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, YICHANG XIONG, GUANGLIANG YANG, HONG HU, GUOFEI GU, AND WENKE LEE

Discovering Hidden Properties to Attack Node.js Ecosystem.

BlackHat'20

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, YICHANG XIONG, GUANGLIANG YANG, HONG HU, GUOFEI GU, AND WENKE LEE

Unexpected Data Dependency Creation and Chaining: A New Attack to SDN.

IEEE S&P'20

FENG XIAO, JINQUAN ZHANG, JIANWEI HUANG, GUOFEI GU, DINGHAO WU, PENG LIU

PatternListener: Cracking Android Pattern Lock Using Acoustic Signals.

ACM CCS'18

Man Zhou, Qian Wang, Jingxiao Yang, Qi Li, **Feng Xiao**, Zhibo Wang, Xiaofeng Chen.

Hacking the Brain: Customize Evil Protocol to Pwn an SDN Controller.

DEFCON'18

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, PENG LIU.

Enabling Secure Location Authentication in Drone (poster).

ACM MobiCom'17

FENG XIAO, MAN ZHOU, YOUCHENG LIYE, JINGXIAO YANG, QIAN WANG.

Honors_____

| 2021 | Most Innovative Research Runner-up | Pwnie Award, USA |
|------|--|--------------------|
| 2019 | Chair Fellowship. | Atlanta, USA |
| 2018 | Rednor IST Fellowship. | State College, USA |
| 2018 | ACM CCS Student Travel Grant Award. | Toronto, Canada |
| 2017 | LeiJun Scholarship (Top 1 out of 310). | Wuhan, China |
| 2016 | National Scholarship (Awarded to top 0.2% undergrads nationwide) | Wuhan, China |
| 2015 | Yuanyi Scholarship. | Wuhan, China |

Programming languages

Natively fluent: Java, Python, Node.js

Conversationally fluent: C, PHP, Matlab